# Kasra Aminiyeganeh

kasraay98@gmail.com | 514.433.3957 | Montreal, Canada

# **EDUCATION**

## **CONCORDIA UNIVERSITY**

M.Sc. IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING 2023/01 | Montreal, CA

## LINKS

Github:// ThaKay LinkedIn:// Kasra Aminiyeganeh Twitter:// @Thekayquality

# **COURSEWORK**

#### GRADUATE

Cloud Computing Model Driven Development Advanced Software Engineering IoT Networks

(Research Asst. & Teaching Asst.)
Programming Methodology
Real-time Operating Systems
Data Structures And Algorithms

#### **UNDERGRADUATE**

Information Retrieval
Operating Systems
Artificial Intelligence + Practicum
Algorithms and Data Structures
Game Development + Practicum
(Research Asst. & Teaching Asst.)
Embedded Systems
Design and Analysis of Databases
Software Engineering

# SKILLS

## **PROGRAMMING**

Over 10,000 lines:
Java • Shell/Bash • Python • JavaScript •
SQL • C • C++ • HTML/CSS • MTFX

#### **SOFTWARE**

Scrum • SDLC • Unit Testing/TDD •
System Design • Object-Oriented •
Design Patterns • Containerization •
Microservices • Cloud Native • CI/CD •
Infrastructure as Code (IaC) • Serverless
• RESTful API design • RDBMS • NoSQL

## **TECHNOLOGIES**

Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Linux • Docker • Postgresql • Kubernetes (K8s) • Terraform • Jenkins • Version Control (Git) • Unix • Redis • MongoDB

## **ABOUT**

I have delivered software solutions efficiently and professionally for 4 years. I have developed a wide array of apps, from old-school client-server apps using the LAMP stack to the latest serverless, microservice-based cloud native ones built on top of k8s and Docker. Went down the path of managing and deploying applications across various environments, employing techniques like load balancing, auto-scaling, and fault tolerance to guarantee optimal performance, scalability, and high availability. Luckily as a by-product I have honed my ability to smell the code and groom the backlog!

# **EXPERIENCE**

## NATIVE TOUCH | SOFTWARE ENGINEER, FULL-TIME

Jan 2023 - Present | Montreal, Canada

- Developed Python, Node.js, and reviewed code using the Reviewable tool.
- Extended and maintained different parts of the SDK and API to handle advertisement big data pipelines within a fully serverless architecture.
- Utilized Docker and K8s for managing various microservices on the AWS EKS.
- Incorporated CI/CD pipelines using Jenkins, multi-enviornment deployment, and canary testing.
- Used Terraform and Ansible for creating and destroying resources on AWS.

#### **DIGIPAY** | Back-end Engineer, Part-time

Jan 2020 – June 2021 | Tehran, Iran

- Dockerized the Tap Payment solution to be integrated as a microservice within the company's digital wallet app.
- Developed RESTful API routes using Python-Django and improved backend by utilizing SOLID principles and Redis for caching as part of an Agile Scrum team, resulting in a 15% increase in customer payment satisfaction.
- Implemented Unit tests with Pytest for the Back-end system to increase deployment speed by 20%.

#### **OMANTEL** | Network Engineer, Intern

July 2019 - Aug 2019 | Muscat, Oman

- Participated in the Design and maintenance of data-intensive networks and IT infrastructure with over 1M users.
- Practiced Distributed Systems concepts such as Caching and CDNs in a highly-scaled business.

## **PROJECTS**

# FITNESS SUPER-APP | TEAM-LEAD & BACK-END DEVELOPER

July 2019 - Aug 2019 | Muscat, Oman

- Led a team of 4 to develop a cross-platform mobile super application MVP in 5 months, practicing Scrum.
- Employed React Native and Python Django to enable users to register in local gyms, receive training and diet plans by connecting them to a coach, and access correct exercise moves
- Integrated Google Maps to display gym locations and monthly plan costs.
- Incorporated persistent data storage using RESTful APIs to enable cloud-based data storage.
- Leveraged caching for recently accessed training moves.
- Utilized technologies: RESTful APIs, Django, Design Pattern, Git, PostgreSQL, Docker, Redis, Google Map API, and AWS cloud.